A Guide to the Earl H. Hornbarger Collection, 1912-1963
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Earl H. Hornbarger Collection, 1912-1963
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2013-003
0.7 cu. ft. 2 boxes, 1 oversize folder
This collection contains photographs, publications, journals, writings and artifacts pertaining to Earl H. Hornbarger's time as a student at VPI, his later career as an engineer with Westinghouse Electric Company, and his involvement as a VPI alumnus.
Hornbarger, Earl H., (Earl Hampton)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to Special Collections in February 2012.
Biographical Note
Earl Hampton Hornbarger was born in 1898. He graduated from Virginia Agricultural and and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute with a degree in Electrical Engineering in 1921. He later worked for Westinghouse. Hornbarger died in 1967.
Scope and Content
The Earl H. Hornbarger Collection consists of materials relating to his time as a member of the Corps class of 1921 and his later career with Westinghouse Electric Company.
A large majority of the collection relates to Hornbarger's time as a student from 1917 to 1921. It contains a "VPI Memory Book" scrapbook, several banquet brochures and dance cards. There are several artifacts from this time as well, including a pocket bible and a VPI class pin. There is a fold-out pictorial of the entire VPI Corps of Cadets class from 1919-1920, Barracks 1-4. The collection also contains several pamphlets and articles pertaining to Hornbarger's Class of 1921 Reunion in 1962.
Several magazine and book publications pertain to Hornbarger's engineering career with the Westinghouse Electric Company, including a Westinghouse Instruction book written by Hornbarger, a edition of Westinghouse Magazine, and several photos related to Westinghouse production projects.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series: Personal Papers and VPI Memorabilia. Personal Papers includes materials from Hornbarger's professional career, plus some personal artifacts. VPI Memorabilia contains photographs, artifacts, and other ephemera from his tenure as a student.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Corps of Cadets
Contents List
- Personal Papers
  - "Electric Breaking Methods" A Publication By E. A. Hornbarger (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Photographs of Equipment for Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel Project (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Photograph of Propulsion Control U.S.S Colorado (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Program for Retirement Dinner in Honor of E. A. Hornbarger (Box-folder 1-4)
  - "Silent Sentinels" Westinghouse Productive Relays (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Westinghouse Magazine, January 1936 (Box-folder 2-3)
  - Westinghouse Propulsion Control Equipment Instruction Book, 1943 (Box-folder 2-4)
  - New Testament Pocket Bible, C: 1918 (Box-folder 2-5)
- VPI Memorabilia
  - VPI Banquet Menu Cards, 1936 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - VPI 1921 Golden Jubilee Ball Dance Card (Box-folder 1-7)
  - VPI Class of 1921 Graduation- Program, Invitation, and Honors List (Box-folder 1-8)
  - VPI Memory Book, 1917-1921 (Box-folder 2-1)
  - VPI Class of 1921 Reunion, 1962 (Box-folder 2-2)
  - VPI Brass Class Insignia (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Photograph of VPI Corps of Cadets, 1919-1920 (Folder 1)